Guide to the records of the Musical Acoustics Research Library (MARL) M1711
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3. Arthur H. Benade Collection, 1956-1987; 19.182 Linear Feet; Between 1982 and late 1987: After cancer was diagnosed in the fall of 1982, Benade made increased use of detailed projections (with many pages hand-drawn) for many of his lectures. Though casual in appearance, these were planned
  - Correspondence - Casson, Donald, 1972-1978 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Caussé, René, 1978-1985 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Coltman, John W., 1965-1974 (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Corey, Gerald, 1970-1979 (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Covey, Paul, 1976 (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Crane, Richard H., 1970 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Cronin, Robert H., 1977-1986 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Cunningham, Robert G., 1970-1978 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Dannenberg, Roger, 1982-1983 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Dawson, Stanley, 1976 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Deaver, Tom, 1974-1987 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Decker, Ken, 1980-1987 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Děkan, Karel, 1973-1985 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Dostrovsky, Sigalia, 1972-1975 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Eisner, Edward, 1966-1972 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Erdesz, Otto, 1977-1978 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Elder, Sam, 1965-1969 (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Finch, Thomas L., 1972-1976 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Fletcher, Neville H., 1972-1984 (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Flyd, Rowland W., 1973 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Fox, Alan, 1966-1978 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Fransson, Frans, 1967-1969 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Galper, Avrahm, 1965-1975 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Gebler, James M., 1972-1982 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Ghosh, Nikhil, 1981 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Gibson, Lee, 1967-1975 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Golber, David, 1981 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Gough, Colin, 1979-1981 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Gregory, Robin, 1969 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Groffy, Franz, 1969 (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Hacklinger, Max, 1977 (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Hailperin, Paul, 1970-1972 (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Hall, Donald, 1984-1987 (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Harris, James R., 1977-1984 (Box 90, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Hausl, Edwin, 1965-1967 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Haynes, Bruce, 1971 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Heinrich, Jane, 1976-1986 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Horvath, Helmuth, 1970-1975 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Hutchins, Carleen, 1964-1968 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Hutchins, Carleen, 1968-1987 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Ibisi, Michael, 1981-1987 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Jameson, George, 1969-1982 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Jameson, George, 1983-1986 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Jansson, Erik, 1973-1987 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Juritz, John W. F., 1976 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Kasha, Michael, 1968 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Keefe, Doug, 1977-1985 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Kent, Earle L. at C. G. Conn LTD. Manufacturers and Distributors of Musical Instruments, 1957-1964 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Kent, Earle L. at C. G. Conn LTD. Manufacturers and Distributors of Musical Instruments, 1966-1978 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Kent, Earle L. at C. G. Conn LTD. Manufacturers and Distributors of Musical Instruments. Publications, 1951-1962 (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Kent, Earle L. at C. G. Conn LTD. Manufacturers and Distributors of Musical Instruments. Research on the Saxophone, 1945-1968 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Killion, Mead C., 1971-1987 (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Kordesch, Martin, 1984-1986 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Krüger, Walther, 1976-1985 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Kujala, Wally, 1971 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Lamberson, Tip, 1968-1981 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Larson, Curt, 1978-1981 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Lawson, Bruce A., 1984-1985 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - G. Leblanc Corporation, Kenosha WI, 1966-1971 (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Leblanc, Leon, 1969-1970 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Ledang, Ola Kai, 1984-1985 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Lenkauskas, Edmundas, 1986 (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Leuba, Christopher, 1961-1974 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Lewin, Frank, 1969 (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Livingston, Larry, 1974 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Mack, John, 1969-1970 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Maloney, Norman, 1965-1970 (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - C.F. Martin Co.; Thompson, Don, 1966-1969 (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Marvin, Robert, 1969-1975 (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - Mazzeo, Rosario, 1968-1983 (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - McClain, Ernest G., 1966-1984 (Box 93, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - McCracken, George.; King Musical Instruments, 1967-1981 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - McIntyre, Michael, 1976-1988 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - McLaughlin, G. E., 1978 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Meyer, Jürgen, 1966-1981 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - D.C. Miller Flute Collection, 1977-1984 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Miller, Harry B., 1986-1987 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Miller, Robert, 1973 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Montagu, Jeremy, 1966-1980 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Murray, Alex, 1969-1980 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Nagi, Yohei, 1971-1973 (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Nagy, Michael, 1979-1986 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Nederveen, C. J., 1964-1968 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Ohio Rubber Co., 1982 (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Olson, Dale R. and F.E. Olds & Sons, Inc., 1961-1962 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Ormestad, Helmut, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Palm, Richard, 1973-1978 (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Patterson, John, 1969-1975 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Merewether, Richard and Paxman Horn Center, 1969 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Pyle, Robert W. Jr., 1965-1983 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Puglisi, Filadelfio, 1973-1979 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Rakowski, Andrzej, 1976-1985 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Raman, C.V., 1969 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Randall, Harry, 1973-1976 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Reuben, Ronald, 1971 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Richards, Bruce, 1980-1984 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Rickey, Martin E., 1979 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Riordan, Frank S. Jr., 1983-1987 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Ro, David H. and Imperial Clevite, 1982 (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Rosenberg, Ellis, 1972-1977 (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Roederer, Juan G., 1972-1978 (Box 95, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Ross, David, 1983 (Box 95, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Sard, Robert D., 1951; vt123xy5936 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Saunders, Frederick A., 1961-1962; yc969xt6209 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Savage, William R., 1976-1977; zr603xn9308 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Savage, William R., 1978-1986; qg624dj2630 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Schaeflein, Jürg, 1967-1986; jz304yf1988 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Schantz, Bruce, 1965-1986; nw657fb0696 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - W. Schreiber & Söhne. Woodwind Instrument Builders, 1972-1981; gq281xr5564 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Schumacher, Robert T., 1972-1981; xd239vd3099 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Selmer Company, 1970-1971; fc090hk2155 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Shackleton, Nicholas, 1968-1973; cz874tx2732 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Shankland, Robert S., 1965-1981 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Shankland, Robert S. Publications, 1958-1980 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Shaw, Edgar A. G., 1976 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Shonle, John I., 1973-1976 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Singer, Lawrence, 1972 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Sluchin, Benny, 1985 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Stat, Daniel, 1974 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Stavash, John C., 1965-1979 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Stetson, Karl A., 1965-1972 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Strong, William J., 1970-1982 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Stubbins, William H., 1969-1975 (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Sundberg, Johan, 1970-1987 (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Tarr, Edward H., 1969-1974 (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Taylor, Charles A., 1971-1977 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Terhardt, Ernst J., 1967-1987 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Thompson, Stephen C., 1977-1983 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Turković, Milan, 1971-1981 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Umans, Stephen, 1983-1987 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Van Hoesen, David K., 1980-1981 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Villchur, Edgar, 1975 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Vogt, Walter W., 1965-1968 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Vogt, Walter W., 1968-1971 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Von Huene, Friedrich. Historical Woodwinds, 1973-1983 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Voxman, Himie, 1971-1987 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Waitzman, Daniel, 1968-1981 (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Waln, Geroge, 1967-1970 (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Warner, Robert E., 1975-1979 (Box 98, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Waterhouse, William R., 1969-1987 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Weidner, Richard T., 1973 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Weinreich, Gabriel, 1975-1987 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Wilding-White, Ray, 1966 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Woodhouse, James, 1982 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Worman, Walter E., 1968-1974 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Worman, Walter E., 1975-1985 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Wright, Dan K., 1970 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Wright, Fulton Jr., 1969-1973 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Young, Charles, 1962-1966 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Young, Niels O., 1971-1972 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Young, Robert W., 1960-1977 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Young, Robert W., 1977-82 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Flute Related, 1962-1968 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    These letters were kept separate from the main alphabetical series following Benade's organization. He labeled this folder: Flute Correspondence.
  - Correspondence - Wind Instruments in the Concert Hall. Materials for a lecture at Parc de la Villette in France, Daniel Commins, (notes, slides, and letters), 1983-1987 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    Arrangement
    These letters were kept separate from the main alphabetical series following Benade's organization.
  - Correspondence - Doubleday & Co. Inc., Publishers (letters and reviews on Benade's book, Horns, Strings and Harmony., 1960-1967 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - On Vito Kushleika’s viola, 1956; on the construction of woodwinds, John C. Stavash and Michael A. Scungio, 1957; On Horns, Strings, and Harmony, 1958-1959; General Theory of Aerophone Operation, F. Neal Eddy, 1959; The American Institute of Physics, Eugene H. Kone, invitation to present a paper, 1959; Permission for publication from Robert M. Sutton, 1959; Constructing a Bassethorn in A, Arthur Ness, 1959; Question on “Mathematical Theory of Woodwind Fingerholes,” Warren B. Cheston, 1960; Sabine formula, Bruce V. Schantz, 1960; Pads and raised tone holes in wood winds, J. F. Feddersen from H. and A. Selmer Inc., 1960; On writing a review for Russell B. Hastings, Physics of Sound, 1960; The flute as an example of an acoustic resonator, R. K. Moore, 1960; Benade's Response to the Scientific American Magazine about Writing on Theobald Boehm, 1960; Responses to Horns, Strings, and Harmony, 1960-1961; G. F. Herrenden Harker exchanges writings with Benade, 1961; Reception of Horns, Strings and Harmony; Invitation to speak at Oberlin College Physics Lecture Series, Robert Weinstock, 1961; on playing two simultaneous notes on a saxophone and “false fingering,” Frank Kofsky, 1961; invitation to speak at a colloquium on acoustics of musical instruments, Iowa State University, D. J. Zaffarano, 1961; Adding foreign authors to the Science Study Series, B. F. Kingsburry, 1961, 1956 - 1961 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Arranging lecture, Radiation and Nonlinear Effects in Wind Instruments,, Iowa State University, D. J. Zaffarano, 1962; Measurements of the radiation pattern of musical instruments, Robin M. Towne, 1962; Lumped-constant transmission line analog to the flute, R. K. Moore, 1962; On building recorders, Dennis Brown, 1962; Author suggestions for Science Study Series, B. F. Kingsbury, 1962; Dynamics of reeds, James Collis, 1962; Building a small portative organ, Richard F. Kohns, 1963; Arranging lecture at Princeton University, Musical Instruments as Nonlinear Oscillators, W. B. Daniels, 1963; Dissonance based on instrumental harmonic spectrums, Harry B. Armstrong, 1963; Free Vibrating Reed Tongue, R.C. Hitchcock, 1963; On the beat-rate calculations in Horns, Strings, and Harmony, J.M. Scott, 1963; Physics of percussion instruments, D. B. Colyer, 1963; Notes on the 66th Meeting of the Acoustical Society of America by G. D. Gifford, 1963; On the wide band phase splitters, D. W. Martin, 1963; On wide-band phase shift networks, W.C. Wayne, Jr. from D. H. Baldwin Co. 1963, 1962 -1963 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - On behalf of Dr. M. S. Vairanapillay, 1964; Edelmann whistle, Kenneth D. Roeder, 1964; Visual tuning device, Theodor B. Rosenthal, 1964; Grant request for studies in physical acoustics of musical instruments to the Cleveland Foundation, 1964; designing an electronic flute, Edmund E. Goodale; Relation of material to tone of musical instruments, L. L. Sudranski, 1966; Effects of vocal cavities on timbre, James Thornton, 1966; Nonlinearities in the mechanical parts of the ear, Frank S. Crawfodr, 1966; Designing a clarinet, Richard A. Page, 1966; Invitation to become head of the Physics Department at University of Maine, John J. Nolde, 1966; Invitation to join the University of Minnesota faculty, Warren B. Cheston, 1966, 1964 - 1966 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - On Transcent and Sustained Waves, University of Minnesota; Visiting Scientists Program in Physics: Talks on Physics and Music for Undergrads; NASA, Cleveland: Wave Physics of Wind Instruments; On Combustion Oscillations, Peter K. Baade, 1967 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Making a flute for Banade, Alfred Sierhuis, (letter and photograph of wooden transverse flute); On the striking point of piano hammers, Wilbur O. Buss; Properties of wood as they relate to musical instruments, M. Nestler; Acoustic properties of tubes with side holes, A. E. Elo Jr., (letters and graph); National Clarinet Clinic lectures on reed mechanisms and bore requirements for a woodwind; Balancing reed mechanisms and bore dimensions to get good intonation and timbre in a clarinet, (letters, diagrams, notes for his lecture and on other presentations); On Benade's talk at Oberlin College: Pulsed and Sustained Waves in Brass Instruments. See also JASA abstract, 1969, (letters and notes); On the shape of a horn cross-section, Edmund D. Allen; Calibration sound source for Carleen Hutchins, Ronald Naspo, 1968; For diagrams and slides for these talks see Writings: box 102 folder 28 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Michigan State Lectures: Practical Acoustics of Woodwind Instruments; Practical Acoustics of Brass Instruments. Dealing with tone, tuning and transients, (letters and speaker's notes); Institute for Teachers of H. S. Physics. Materials on Benade's six weeks of teaching, (letters and travel itinerary); Letters to and from M.M. Kaushik, Laboratory Assistant at the I.I.T. Kanpur. Benade was instrumental in enabling Kaushik to receive advanced training in Physics in the U. S.; On Benade's Asheville-Biltmore College Talk, (letter and notes), 1969 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Letters to and from R. E. Fryxell on editing Jurgen Meyer's paper, 1970; Letter to Warren Creel on the AAAS programs, 1971; On the Publication of an Article on the Physics of Brass for the Journal Scientific American, 1972; Teaching a course on physics and music, Neil L. Lark, 1973; Bore sizes; Choice of diameter scaling, Irving Dayton, 1973; Research subjects at Case Western Reserve University, Armel Boutard, 1973; Pure tone emission form orifices at low flow speed, Angelo A. Moretta, 1973; Useful interpretation of recordings, George Bissinger, 1974; Reeds and staples of baroque, classical, and modern oboes, A. Hoekstra, 1974; Sanders traverso flute, James Pellerite, 1974; Working on Thomas D. Griego's clarinet, 1974; About the 1974 Convention of the National Flute Association. Benade was the chairman of the panel "Acoustics of Flute Tubings and Heads, 1974 Pittsburgh, PA. on this occasion Benade's BCB flute had its first public appearance at the Gala Concert, 1974, (letters, notes for talk, and program); From and to Lowry Riggins. On the slightly flat F in his Mirafone oboe, 1974; Letter to Larry Brady on Benade's talk Woodwinds in the Concert Hall, 1974, (letter and notes); Endorsing Daniel W. Haines' grant requesting the study the mechanical properties of woods and varnishes for stringed instruments, 1974; Cooper scale, E. L. DeFord, 1974; Bells for oboes, English horns, and clarinets, Herbert H. Oberlag, 1974; Neck Proportions in Conical Woodwinds, Experiment by A. Hoekstra, 1974; Sending Otto Eifert the manuscript of his paper "On the Influence of Tone-Hole Design on the Playing Properties of Bassoons," 1973 (letter from 1974); Noise Abatement Problem for Beaumont Hall, Cleveland Ohio,1974, (letters, notes to the pro bono consulting); The beating reed, discussion with John T. Cannon, 1974; Invitation: visiting professorship at University of Michigan, 1974, (letters), 1970 - 1974 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - What Makes a Woodwind Good? Waves and Sound. Two lectures for Heidelberg College, (letter to Stanley Schmidt and lecture notes); On Grove's Dictionary of Music and Musicians Entry, (letters, graph and figure for entry); Acoustical conditions of McGaw Chapel, Arthur E. Palmer; Water keys for French horns and rounding corners of valves, Josiah Fisk; The Pursuit of Woodwinds, William Hartmann, (includes notes); How to Recognize a Good Flute and How to Adjust and Play it for Best Tone and Response. For Flute Seminar, Indiana University, School of Music, (letters and notes for talk); Musical Instruments. Article for the Encyclopedia of Physics for graduate students and professionals, (typescript, letters); On the almost completed Fundamentals of Musical Acoustics, and on musical wood, Robert Fryxell; Overview of the best "old" days cornet players, James Sudranski; On Robert H. Johns thesis, The Motion of the Bowed String; Achieving greater volume in a clavichord, Wade Greene, 1975 (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Consulting on air jet feedback oscillators and the construction/adjusting of recorders, S. G. Forbes; Discussion on recording, analysis, and interpretation of musical waveforms, Richard Dilling; The Pursuit of Woodwinds. Science in the Public Interest, lecture for the University of Colorado, (lecture notes and letters); Lecture invitation, Hiram College, 1976, (letter by Arthur Berman); Instructional Television Sequence on Physics of Musical Instruments, 1976, (announcement, notes for talks, and letters); On Karl Stetson "Mode Doubling and the Production of Wolf Tones," Robert E. Fryxell; Vibration physics of instruments, room acoustics, and our auditory systems, Danny H. Mills; From Player to Listener, Via Instrument, Room, and Ear. Lecture for the University of Toledo, Physics Colloquium, (announcement, lecture notes, and letters); Letter from Dave G. Monet on Pipe Organs; Letter to R. B. Lindsay, editor of the Acoustical Society of America. On a text on musical acoustics for the AIP brochure (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Detailed feedback on Fundamentals of Musical Acoustics, R. H. Silsbee and Benade's response; Reeds and oboes, Sture Carlund; On Benade's review on musical acoustics, Manfred Clynes D. Sc.; Interplay of physics, music, and perception, H. Metzelaar, (letters and preliminary form of Benade's paper for the ICA meeting in Madrid); Description of some historical woodwind instruments, C. H. Grimm; On Worman's result, John Wessner; Transient analyzer, R. Dean Ayers; On Fundamentals of Musical Acoustics, 1977, Dana L. Johnson, (letters and diagram); Designing an electric trombone, Peter Hubbe; Report on the Roxboro School auditorium acoustics, Felix Kraus; Designing a vertical flute and the T-headjoint, Steven Kirk; Becoming an instrument repair specialist, Connie Vial; Questions related to Fundamentals of Musical Acoustics, J. Ross Macdonald; Review of Joseph Morgan's manuscript The Physical Basis of Musical Sounds; Adjusting Anthony Cecere's bass clarinet; Questions on Horns, Strings, and Harmony, Martin B. Tittle (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Europe Summer, pre-travel letters: on the tenora (tenor shawm); Meeting at IRCAM; Acoustic Notes by Steve Thompson; Conference on Musical Acoustics (Catgut Acoustical Society), Cambridge, England, (program, list of participants, arrangements, Benade's handwritten Sketch of Helmholtz Mathematics); Workshop on Physical and Neurophysical Foundations of Music, Ossiach, Austria, 1977, (program, abstracts, pamphlets, lecture notes, and letters); 9th International Congress on Acoustics, Madrid. Plenary Session Talk on Recent Worldwide Developments on Musical Acoustics, (typescript and handwritten notes of talk, notes on other talks, letters); Post Europe trip letters, correspondents include: Maurice Hancock, Carleen M. Hutchins, Robert E. Fryxell (Box 116, Folder 3)